In the previous video,
在上个视频中
we used MLPs to decode images of handwritten numerical digits.
我们使用 MLP 来解码手写数字图像
Before feeding a gray scale image to an MLP,
在向 MLP 提供灰度图像之前
we had to first convert its matrix to a vector.
我们首先需要将其矩阵转换为向量
This vector was then fed as input to an MLP with two hidden layers.
然后将此向量输入到具有两个隐藏层的 MLP 中
We saw that it was a perfectly valid model for classifying images in the MNIST dataset.
我们发现该模型非常适合分类 MNIST 数据集中的图像
In fact, we got less than 2% error on our held out test images.
实际上 测试图像的误差低于 2%
But for other image classification problems,
但是对于其他图像分类问题
where we might need to analyze more
我们可能需要分析更复杂的现实图像
sophisticated real world images with more complicated patterns,
这些图像的规律更复杂
we'll need a different technique.
我们需要采用其他技巧
In this video, towards motivating and defining CNNs,
在此视频中 在构建和定义 CNN 时
we specify a few improvements that eliminate some of the drawbacks and
我们做出了一些改进 并消除了
limitations that we encounter when performing image classification with MLPs.
在用 MLP 进行图像分类时遇到的一些不足和限制情况
Specifically, we'll adjust two important issues.
具体而言 我们将调整两个重要问题
First, we've seen that MLPs use a lot of parameters.
首先 我们看到 MLP 使用了很多参数
The MLP from the previous video,
上个视频中的 MLP
for our very small 28 by 28 images,
处理的是非常小的 28 x 28 图像
already contained over half a million parameters.
就已经包含了超过 50 万的参数
You can imagine that the computational complexity for
可以想象即使是中等大小的图像
even moderately sized images could get out of control pretty fast.
计算复杂程度也会很快就失控
Another issue is that we throw away all of
另一个问题是当我们将图像矩阵展平为向量时
the 2-D information contained in an image when we flatten its matrix to a vector.
丢失了图像中包含的所有二维信息
This spatial information or knowledge of where
这种空间信息或
the pixels are located in reference to each other is
像素相互之间的位置信息
relevant to understanding the image and could aid
可以帮助我们理解图像
significantly towards elucidating the patterns contained in the pixel values.
并非常有助于发现像素值中包含的规律
This suggests that we need an entirely new way of processing image input,
这表明我们需要一种全新的方式来处理图像输入
where the 2-D information is not entirely lost.
这样才不会完全丢失二维信息
CNNs will address these problems by using layers that are more sparsely connected.
CNN 将通过使用更加稀疏互联的层级来解决这些问题
Where the connections between layers are
层级之间的连接
informed by the 2-D structure of the image matrix.
由图像矩阵的二维结构确定
Furthermore, CNNs will accept our matrix as input.
此外 CNN 将接受矩阵输入
For illustration, consider a toy example with four by four images of handwritten digits.
假设有个 4x4 的手写数字图像小例子
Our goal remains the same,
我们的目标保持不变
we'd like to classify the digit that's depicted in the image.
我们想要对图像中的数字进行分类
After converting the four by four matrix to a 16 dimensional vector,
将 4x4 的矩阵转换为 16 维向量后
we can supply the vector as input to an MLP.
我们可以将向量当做输入提供给 MLP
We construct an MLP with a single hidden layer with four nodes.
我们构建一个具有一个隐藏层（四个节点）的 MLP
The output layer has 10 nodes.
输出层有 10 个节点
As in the MLP in the previous video,
和上个视频中的 MLP 一样
the output has a softmax activation function and returns a 10-dimensional vector
输出有一个 softmax 激活函数并返回一个十维向量
containing the probability that the image depicts
包含图像描述的 0 到 9 数字
each of the possible digits zero through nine.
每个数字的可能概率
If we've trained our model well,
如果对模型训练的很好
the vector will predict that a seven is depicted in the image with high probability.
向量将预测图像中的数字为 7 的概率很高
But let's clean up this figure by replacing
但是我们对此图处理下
this detailed depiction with the suggested output layer.
将详细的描绘替换为建议的输出层
Here, the box annotated with it's a seven,
这里 包含“it's a 7!”的方框
is just shorthand notation for an output layer which predicts a seven.
是描绘 7 的输出层的快捷记法
Just looking at this MLP,
直接看下这个 MLP
it becomes apparent that there may be some redundancy.
就很清楚可能存在多余的内容
Does every hidden node need to be connected to every pixel in the original image?
每个隐藏节点都需要与原始图像中的每个像素相连吗？
Perhaps not, consider breaking the image into four regions.
或许不需要 可以将图像分成四个区域
Here, color coded as red,
用红色 绿色
green, yellow, and blue.
黄色和蓝色表示
Then, each hidden node could be connected to
每个隐藏节点都可能
only the pixels in one of these four regions.
仅与这四个区域中的某个区域的像素相连
Here, each headed node sees only a quarter of the original image.
每个隐藏节点仅看到原始图像的四分之一
In the case of the previous fully connected layer,
对于刚才的完全连接层
every hidden node was responsible for gaining
每个隐藏节点都需要
an understanding of the entire image all at once.
同时了解整个图像
With this new regional breakdown and the assignment of
现在 经过新的细分
small local groups of pixels to different hidden nodes,
并将一小部分像素分配给不同的隐藏节点
every hidden node finds patterns in only one of the four regions in the image.
每个隐藏节点都发现图像四个区域之一存在的规律
Then, each hidden node still reports to the output layer where
然后 每个隐藏节点依然向输出层汇报
the output layer combines the findings for
输出层将从每个区域单独发现的规律
the discovered patterns learned separately in each region.
结合到一起
This so called locally connected layer
这个所谓的局部连接层
uses far fewer parameters than a densely connected layer.
比密集连接层使用的参数少了很多
It's less prone to overfitting and truly
更不容易过拟合
understands how to tease out the patterns contained in image data.
并且真正的了解如何发现图像数据中包含的规律
We can rearrange each of these vectors as a matrix.
我们可以将每个向量重新排列成矩阵
Where now the relationships between the nodes in each layer are more obvious.
现在每层中的节点之间的关系更清晰
We could expand the number of patterns that we're able to
我们可以扩展我们能够发现的规律数量
detect while still making use of
同时依然利用
the 2-D structure to selectively and conservatively
二维结构选择性并谨慎地
add weights to the model by introducing more hidden nodes.
向模型增加权重 方法是引入更多隐藏节点
Where each is still confined to analyzing a single small region within the image.
每个节点依然只需分析图像中的一个小区域
The red nodes in the hidden layer are still
隐藏层中的红色节点
only connected to the red nodes in the input layer.
依然只与输出层中的红色节点相连
With the same color coding for all other colors.
其他所有颜色也同样
After all we saw in the previous videos on neural networks that by expanding the number
毕竟在看了之前关于神经网络的视频后 我们发现
of nodes in the hidden layer we can discover more complex patterns in our data.
通过增加隐藏层中的节点数量 我们能够从数据中发现更复杂的规律
We now have two collections of hidden nodes where each collection
我们现在拥有两组隐藏节点
contains nodes responsible for examining a different region of the image.
每组包含的节点都负责检查图像的不同区域
It will prove useful to have each of the hidden nodes
事实证明让一组中的每个隐藏节点
within a collection share a common group of weights.
都具有共同的权重很有用
The idea being that different regions within
原理是图像中的不同区域
the image can share the same kind of information.
可能会具有相同种类的信息
In other words, every pattern that's relevant towards
换句话说 每个有助于理解图像的规律
understanding the image could appear anywhere within the image.
都可能出现在图像的某个位置
Perhaps the simplest way to see how this parameter sharing will help
了解这一参数共享模式可以如何帮助神经网络
our neural network classify objects is through a higher resolution image example.
分类对象的最简单方式是查看一个高分辨率图像示例
Say you have an image,
假设有一个图像
and you want your network to say it's an image containing a cat.
你想要网络表示它是一个包含猫咪的图像
It doesn't matter where the cat is.
无论猫在何处
It's still an image with the cat.
依然是含有猫的图像
If your network has to learn about kittens in
如果网络需要单独了解在左上角
the left corner and kittens in the right corner independently.
和右上角的猫咪
That's a lot of work that it has to do.
那么工作量会很大
Instead, we tell the network explicitly that objects and images
相反 我们明确告诉网络无论对象位于左边还是右边
are largely the same whether they're on the left or the right of the picture.
对象和图像都基本一样
And this is partially accomplished through weight sharing.
通过权重共享可以部分实现这一效果
All of these ideas will motivate so-called convolutional layers,
所有这些理论都朝着卷积层发展
which we present in the next video.
我们将在下个视频中介绍卷积层